&gt;&gt; Hello and.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Welcome to what's new in Core
欢迎大家参加这个主题会议“Core Spotlight 的
Spotlight.
新功能”
I'm John Hornkvist, Senior
我是 John Hornkvist
Manager for Core Spotlight and
Core Spotlight 的高级经理
joining me today will be my
今天将与我一同讲解的还有
colleague Lyn Fong.
我的同事 Lyn Fong
Today, we'll cover some new
今天我们会介绍一些新的 API
APIs, Core Spotlight on macOS,
macOS 系统中的 Core Spotlight
Drag-and-Drop, Quick Look
Drag-and-Drop 拖放功能
previews, and then we'll give an
还有 Quick Look 预览功能
update on ranking before
我们还会介绍一下排名更新
finishing with a review of
最后还要对索引与搜索功能
indexing and search.
做一番回顾
So, let's jump right into macOS.
那么  我们首先开始介绍 macOS 的新功能
Core Spotlight on macOS is the
macOS 中的 Core Spotlight
exact same API as in iOS so it's
和 iOS 中的 API 并无不同
great for cross-platform apps.
所以 它非常适用于跨平台 App
It's already used by Notes and
在此之前  Core Spotlight
Safari and because it's
已经应用于备忘录和 Safari
cross-platform CoreData
由于它的跨平台特征
Spotlight support has been
CoreData Spotlight 支持
reimplemented using Core
再次获得运用推广
Spotlight and is now available
目前它已经同时适用于
for both iOS and macOS.
iOS 和 macOS 系统
Core Spotlight is great for
Core Spotlight 对数据库和批量扫描
databases and shoeboxes where
来说非常好用
your app has full control over
你的 App 可以借此而实现对内容的
the contents.
完全控制
It's not for items that the user
它并不运用于
monitors in the finder, for that
用户在 Finder 中监视的项
the classic Spotlight API still
因为经典的 Spotlight API 还存在
exists and still works great.
而且性能极好
Finally, the Core Spotlight API
最后一点  由于 Core Sporlight API 是
is per user, so there's no
以单独用户为基础 所以用户之间
sharing.
不可分享
For those of you who are new to
在座各位可能有人
Core Spotlight we'll review the
不熟悉 Core Spotlight
basic concepts later in the
稍后我们会把它的基础概念
session.
回顾一下
An important new feature in iOS
iOS 11 里一个重要的新功能就是
11 is Drag-and-Drop and of
拖放功能
course, Drag-and-Drop is very
当然了  它对于 Mac 来说
important to the Mac as well.
也非常重要
Drag-and-Drop with Core
带有 Core Spotlight 的拖放功能
Spotlight is built on the
是建立在承诺的概念
concept of promises.
基础之上
You make the promise of indexing
如果你建立了标引时间的承诺
time and then you fulfill it
等到用户拖放一个
when the user drops a Core
Core Spotlight 项以后
Spotlight item later.
你就要实现这个承诺
So, let's see this in action.
那么 我们来看看实际操作
We start the drag in Spotlight
首先我们在 Spotlight 里开始拖动
and then we hit the Home button
之后我们按下 Home 键
to go to SpringBoard where we
回到 SpringBoard
can enter notes and we can drop
在这里 我们能够进入备忘录
the image.
把那张图片拖放下来
This is an awesome accelerator
这是个炫酷的加速功能
letting users get to the content
可以让用户非常迅速地
incredibly quickly.
获取内容
Now you may wonder what's
现在你也许很好奇
actually going on behind the
它究竟是如何在后台
scenes.
运作的
First your app indexes items and
首先 你的 App 对各个项进行索引
each item carries a promise.
每一项都带有一个承诺
Your app quits and sometime
你的 App 随即退出  稍过一会儿
later the user runs a query in
用户在 Spotlight 中
Spotlight.
运行查询
The user drags the item in
用户在 Spotlight 中拖动项目
Spotlight and Spotlight creates
Spotlight 创建一个承诺
a promise that gets sent to the
这个承诺会被发送到
drag receiver.
接收拖放项的 App
The app picks the type it wants
当这个 App 选出它需要的类型后
and the request goes back to
请求又返回到
Spotlight.
Spotlight
Spotlight will then call your
Spotlight 随后将根据
application or your app
类型和项目信息来调用
extension with the type and item
你的应用或你的
information.
App Extension
So, then you provide the data
然后是你提供数据
and it gets passed to Spotlight.
数据被传递至 Spotlight
Of course, the receiving app it
当然 接收的 App 是能够
can take the content.
获取内容的
This might look complicated, but
这看起来可能有些复杂
there's actually not that much
但你真正需要做的
that you have to do.
并不是太多
Your first task is deciding what
你的第一个任务是决定
drag types to support.
支持哪些拖放类型
Drag types use uniform type
拖放类型使用统一的
identifiers or UTI types which
类型标识符或 UTI 类型
are the [inaudible] of the
这些是系统的[音质不清晰]
These provide a uniform way of
它们提供了某种统一的方法
describing types in our
来描述我们制定的层级当中
hierarchy going from the most to
不同类型
the least specific.
从最特殊到最不特殊的类型
You can find great information
要想获取有关统一类型标识符的信息
about uniform type identifiers
请访问以下网址
on developer.apple.com.
developer.apple.com
You can define new types for
你可以给你的应用程序
your application, but for
定义新类型
Drag-and-Drop we want you to
但对于拖放功能 我们希望大家还是
declare types that are
公布那些众所周知的类型
well-known so that other
这样有利于其他应用程序
applications can receive the
对你要提供的数据
data that you have to offer.
进行接收
As an example, a note taking app
例如 一个做笔记记录的 App
might have its own UTI type as a
可能使用自己的 UTI 类型
type of its contents, but it
来作为其内容的一种类型
might advertise that it can
但它可能会对外宣称
provide RTF, HTML and plaintext
如果某个项目被拖放的时候
when an item is dropped.
自己可以提供 RTF HTML 和纯文本
So that's types.
那么这就是类型
Now how do we let Spotlight know
现在来看看 我们怎样让 Spotlight 知道
what can be provided?
哪些是可以提供的
For that there are three new
关于这一问题
attributes in
CSSearchableAttributeSet
CSSearchableAttributeSet.
具有三个新属性
You can promise a data
你可以承诺一项数据表示
representation, a file
一个将被复制的
representation which will get
文件表示形式
copied or an in-place file
或者是一个本地文件表示
representation if your data is
如果你的数据被保存
saved [inaudible] copying.
并用于复制的话
As for the designing provider,
至于设计的提供者
you should specify the highest
你首先应该确定它是
fidelity representation first.
精准程度最高的表示
So how is it used?
那么应该怎样使用它呢？
You create the
你应该像往常一样把
CSSearchableItemAttributeSet as
CSSearchableItemAttributeSet
usual.
创建出来
In this case, we already have an
在这个实例中 我们已经有一个
image file so we'll provide that
图片文件 所以我们将它
for the file type identifier.
交给文件类型标识符处理
And we can also convert the
我们也能转换图片[音质不清晰]
image [inaudible] so declared it
按照先前的宣称内容  它可以
can provide plaintext as data.
提供纯文本数据
So that's our promise.
这就是我们的承诺
Next, let's look at how to
接下来我们来看
produce that.
如何生成它
When the user drops items, your
当用户拖动放置项目时
extension will get called and in
你的 Extentsion 会被调用
the rare case that your app
在极少数情况下
happens to be running this may
你的 App 恰好正在运行
be your app's index delegate
那么这可能会变为你的 App
instead.
索引委托
Depending on what the receiving
根据接收 App 的请求内容
app requested one out of two
上述两种方法中的一种
methods will get called.
将会被调用
If they ask for data or they ask
如果它们请求数据或者
for a type or you could provide
某一类型 或是你能够提供数据
data, the data method gets
数据方法将被调用
called and takes a searchable
并且获取可搜索的索引
index, an item identifier, and a
项目标识符和
type identifier and you're
类型标识符  而你则应当返回
expected to return the data
数据对象
The file URL method takes the
文件 URL 方法采用
same arguments and additionally
相同的参数 再加上
Booleans specifying whether an
一些布尔值  从而确定是否
in-place file should be
应当提供本地文件
The implementation of the data
数据方法的执行情况
method might look as follows.
大体如下所示
We look at the model object for
我们查看项标识符的
the item identifier, we check
模型对象
the type that's being requested,
还要检查正在请求的类型
and then we produce data
然后再生成相应的
accordingly.
数据
The implementation of the file
文件 URL 方法的
URL method is very similar.
执行过程和它非常类似
Once again, we look at the model
我们再次查看
object for the item identifier,
项目标识符的模型对象
check the type that's being
检查正在请求的类型
requested, but here we produce a
但在这里我们要生成
file.
一个文件
And that's actually all you need
实际上 这些就是你在 iOS 和 macOS 上
to do for Drag-and-Drop on both
使用拖放功能
iOS and macOS.
需要做的所有操作
So, to summarize the new API.
那么 我们来总结一下这个新的 API
You declare and promise drag
在标引的时候
types [inaudible] indexing time.
你要声明并承诺拖动类型
The Core Spotlight extension is
Core Spotlight Extension
critical, it will get launched
至为关键 它将获得启动
to fulfill your promises.
以便完成你的承诺
Make producing the data as fast
用户需要尽快生成数据
as possible, the user will be
他将等待
waiting for the drag to finish.
拖曳动作的完成
And of course, the new API is
当然 新的 API 同时适用于
for both macOS and iOS.
macOS 和 iOS 系统
Next, Lyn is going to come
接下来 Lyn 会
onstage to tell you all about
上台为大家介绍
Quick Look previews for Core
Core Spotlight 的 Quick Look
Spotlight.
预览功能
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Hi [inaudible], let's talk
&gt;&gt; 嗨 我是 Lyn 我们来谈谈
about Quick Look previews for
可用于 Core Spotlight 项目的
your Core Spotlight items.
Quick Look预览功能
On iOS Spotlight shows previews
在 iOS 上 当你通过 3D Touch
of your content when you 3-D
触发 Peek and Pop 时
touch to Peek and Pop.
Spotlight 会显示出内容预览
By default, Spotlight shows a
在默认状态下  Spotlight 会根据
text only preview based on the
你在 Core Spotlight 项目中的文本
text in your Core Spotlight
显示出只读文本预览
item, but now you can customize
但现在你可以通过
your preview by adopting a Quick
采用 Quick Look 预览 Extension
Look preview extension.
来自定义你的预览内容
So, this is an example of a
看 这是默认的
default Core Spotlight preview.
Core Spotlight 预览示例
If you've tried Peek and Popping
如果你曾经对 iOS 10 中的 Core Spotlight 项目
on a Core Spotlight item in iOS
进行过 Peek and Pop 操作
10 this may look familiar.
那么这幅画面看起来就很熟悉了
This is an example of what your
这是一个示例 它表明
preview could look like by
在采用 Quick Look 预览 Extension 后
adopting a Quick Look preview
你的预览内容可能是
extension.
这个样子
This area here is where your
这个区域是
preview will be displayed and it
你的预览内容显示区域
comes from a view controller in
它来自于你的 Extension 中的
your extension.
一个视图控制器
So, let's talk about how we go
那么 我们来谈谈
about implementing one of these
要如何实现这些
extensions.
Extension 功能
The Core Spotlight previews use
Core Spotlight 预览使用了一种
a Quick Look preview SDK which
Quick Look 预览 SDK
is new to iOS this year and
它是 iOS 今年新增加的
comes with a shiny new Xcode
并带有很炫酷的新型 Xcode
template.
模板
When you create your target from
当你从这个模板里创建目标时
this template you will get an
你将获得一个
extension Info.plist and if we
Extension Info.plist
take a look at that plist under
如果我们在 NSExtension 属性下
NSExtension attributes you'll
查看这个 plist
see the QL supports searchable
你将看到 QL 对可搜索
items attribute.
项目属性的支持
For Core Spotlight previews you
关于 Core Spotlight 预览
want that set to yes.
你应设置为 Yes
This lets us know that your
这会让我们知道你的
Quick Look preview extension
Quick Look 预览 Extension
supports Core Spotlight items.
将支持 Core Spotlight 的项
So, let's take a look at the
现在我们来看一下这个
API.
API
When you create your target, you
当你在创建目标时
will get a view controller with
将会运用
this method, preparePreviewOf
preparePreviewOfSearchableItem 这个方法
SearchableItem.
来获取视图控制器
This is what will get called
当你需要预览时
when a preview is required.
就会调用这个方法
In this method, you will get an
通过这个方法 你将获得一个
identifier, this is the Core
标识符 对于你的结果来说
Spotlight identifier unique to
这是独一无二的 Core Spotlight
your result.
标识符
You'll get a query string which
你将获得一个查询字符串
is the string the user searched
这是用户已经搜索到的字符串
for to get to your result.
目的是要获取你的结果
This is helpful if you want to
这非常有助于
highlight content relevant to
你在预览中突出显示
the search in your preview.
与搜索相关的内容
And finally, you will get a
最后 你会得到一个
completion handler that you have
完成句柄
to call once you're done.
一旦完成操作 你必须调用它
So, debugging a Core Spotlight
因此 调试 Core Spotlight
preview extension is different
预览 Extension 有别于典型的
from debugging a typical
Extension 调试
extension, but don't worry it's
不过别担心 它还是
still easy.
很容易的
Instead of picking a host app
你不必选择一个 Host App
and launching your extension
然后再从这个 App 里
from that host app you'll be
启动你的 Extension
launching your extension from
你可以直接从 Spotlight 里
Spotlight directly.
启动 Extention
So, when Xcode asks you for an
所以 当 Xcode 需要你启动 App 时
app on launch pick any app, you
你可以启动任何一个
won't be using it, instead
因为你不会使用它
you'll go to Spotlight, look for
而是会转到 Spotlight
your Core Spotlight item and
查找你的 Core Spotlight 项
then Peek and Pop.
然后进行 Peek and Pop
Xcode will automatically attach
Xcode 将自动连接到
to your extension for you.
你的 Extension
So, let's take a look at this
那么让我们通过演示来
workflow with a demo.
看看这个工作流程
So, before we begin the app that
开始演示之前  我想告诉大家
you will see in this demo is
这次演示要用到的 App
available as sample code so feel
是一个示例代码
free to take a look after the
大家会后可以
session.
随意观看它
So, let's start by taking a look
那么 让我们先看看
at our main app.
主应用程序
So here we have a simple app,
这里有一个简单的 App
it's just a list of pictures.
它只是一个图片列表
If you select one of the
如果你选中其中一张图片
pictures you get a more detailed
你将获得更详细的视图
view with a title, a rating and
包括标题 评分和
some description.
一些描述
So, let's see if we try to find
那么  我们来看看  如果在 Spotlight 中
a picture in Spotlight and Peek
找一张照片 并对它进行 Peek and Pop
and Pop on it.
会是怎样的情况
So, there's item.
这里填入项的名称
Oops, it popped right in.
哎呀 它直接打开了
So, there's a bit of text, it's
嗯 这里有一些文字描述
not the greatest.
这不算最神奇
Let's see if we can do better.
我们来看看能不能做的更好
So back in Xcode here I'm going
我们回到 Xcode 界面
to add a new target from the
在这里我将
Quick Look preview extension
从 Quick Look 预览 Extension 模板里
template and we'll call that
添加一个新目标
pictures preview extension for
我们调用 iOS 中的图片预览 Extension
We'll go ahead and activate
我们要继续操作
that.
激活它
One thing I should mention is
有一点我想提一下
that the view controller that we
我们在 App 里
saw in the app is in a framework
看到的视图控制器
so that it can share across
是位于一个框架里的 这样它可以
multiple targets.
跨越多个目标实现共享
If you have code or resources to
如果你有代码或资源可以
share across targets we suggest
跨目标共享 我们建议你
you use the same approach.
使用相同的手段
So, I'm going to go ahead and
好 我继续操作
import that framework now.
现在引入那个框架
And then we can jump into the
然后我们就能跳到
meat of this file.
这个文件的实质内容
PreparePreview
PreparePreviewOfSscearchableItem
OfSearchableItem, this is the
这是你在
same method you saw in the
幻灯片中看到的同样
slides.
的方法
And here we have the identifier
这里我们有标识符
and what we're going to do is
接下来我们就要
use that identifier to find a
用这个标识符来
picture with a matching
找到带有匹配标识符的
identifier.
图片
And once we have that picture we
一旦我们得到了那张图片
can just go ahead and set up our
我们就可以用它来
view controller with that
针对这张图片而设置视图
picture.
控制器
Again, this is the same view
看 这就是大家在主应用程序里
controller you saw in the main
看到的同一个
app.
视图控件
If you have a lightweight view
如果你在主应用程序中
controller in your main app you
有一个轻量级的视图控制器
can certainly use the same
你当然也可以使用
approach.
同样的方法
If your view controller is more
如果你的视图控制器
memory or speed intensive you
内存更大或速度更快
might want to consider making a
你可能要考虑
lighter weight version for this
为此制定一个级别稍低的
purpose.
版本
So, then we're going to go ahead
我们继续操作
and present it.
把它展示出来
Here I have a little printout so
我在这里加了一点 PrintOut 参数 这样
I can see when Xcode has
当 Xcode 连接好以后我就可以看到
attached and finally, we call
最后 我们调用
that completion handler.
完成句柄
So, let's go and give this a
那么我们来试一试
spin.
看看效果如何
So, as I mentioned, it doesn't
就像我刚才提过的
matter what you pick here you're
在这里选什么不重要
not going to use it, we're going
因为你不会使用它 我们准备
to pick pictures because that's
挑选照片 因为这是我们的
our app.
App
So, there's pictures and we're
这里有些照片
going to head right back into
我们将直接返回 Spotlight
Spotlight and we're going to try
然后再一次尝试
Peek and Popping again.
Peek and Pop 操作
And there's our preview.
这就是我们的预览
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
And you can see from the
现在你可以通过
printout in Xcode that we have
Xcode 里的 PrintOut 看到
successfully attached and now we
我们已经连接成功
can go ahead and debug.
现在我们可以继续进行调试了
So, as you saw implementing a
所以  正如大家所看到的
Quick Look preview extension can
执行 Quick Look 预览 Extension
be very simple, especially if
可以非常简单 特别是当你
you already have a view
已经有一个视图控制器
controller to display your
来显示你的内容
content.
的时候
Maybe the view controller in
也许你的主应用程序里的
your main app is lightweight
视图控制器已经是轻量级的了
already or maybe you've got a
或许在你的 App 里已经
lightweight version for 3-D
安装了一个适用于 3D Touch 的
touch in your app.
轻量级版本
Either way, you can simply reuse
无论哪种情况 你都可以
that view controller here.
重复使用那个视图控制器
Some final tips for your
最后再为你的 Extension 提供一些
extension.
小建议
A loading spinner will show
如果你还没有调用完成句柄
until you call that completion
将会出现一个加载转轮
handler so call it as soon as
所以你应该调用完成句柄
you can.
越早越好
You can expect to see that
当 Xcode 首次与你的 Extension
spinner when Xcode is attaching
相连接时
to your extension for the first
你就可以看到那个转轮
time like in the demo.
就像演示中这样
But once it has already attached
可是一旦连接成功
or if you're not running in
或者你没有
Xcode you want to see your
在 Xcode 中运行
preview immediately.
你会马上就想看到预览内容
This is an extension so memory
这是一个 Extension
is limited, be efficient.
存储空间是有限的 所以要有效率
And finally, once you call that
最后 一旦你调用了那个
completion handler your job is
完成句柄
done, don't do any more
你的工作就结束了
background work after the fact.
此后就不要再进行任何后台操作了
So that's Core Spotlight
这就是 iOS 中的
previews on iOS.
Core Sportlight 预览
The Quick Look preview SDK also
Quick Look 预览 SDK
supports file-based previews and
也支持基于文件的预览
for that see the building great
相关内容可观看
documents based apps in iOS 11
“让基于文档的 App 在 iOS 11 里打造得更为精彩”
session.
这一会议
So, as John mentioned, Core
正如 John 所说
Spotlight is also coming to
macOS 平台也迎来了 Core Spotlight
macOS and just like on iOS you
你可以自定义你的预览
can customize your preview.
就像在 iOS 里一样
On macOS a preview is shown when
在 macOS 上 当你在 Spotlight 窗口中
you select a search result in
选择搜索结果时
the Spotlight window.
预览便会显示出来
Here you really do want to
此时你确实很想给自己的
implement a Quick Look preview
Core Spotlight 执行一个
extension for your Core
Quick Look 预览 Extension
Spotlight item because Spotlight
因为 macOS 中的
on macOS does not have a default
Spotlight 不具有
preview.
默认预览功能
So, this is what it's going to
所以 在没有 Quick Look
look like without a Quick Look
预览 Extension 的情况下
preview extension.
你看到的情况就是这样
And this is what it could look
如果有了这个 Extension
like with one.
情况就会是这样子
This area here is where your
这个区域就是你的
preview will be displayed and
预览内容的展示区域
just like on iOS it comes from a
和 iOS 里的情况一样
view controller in your
它来自于 Extension 里的
extension.
视图控制器
So, you can do just about
所以 你可以完成常规视图
anything a regular view can do.
能做的任何事情
Debugging a Core Spotlight Quick
对 macOS 上的一个
Look preview extension on macOS
Core Spotlight Quick Look
is again different from
预览 Extension 进行调试  同样有别于
debugging a typical extension
调试典型的 Extension
and also different from the iOS
它和 iOS 里的工作流程
workflow.
也不相同
Because Spotlight's window
因为当另外一个 App 获得聚焦后
vanishes when another app gets
Spotlight 窗口就会消失
focused it can be difficult to
所以很难在 Xcode 里
work with breakpoints in Xcode.
使用断点
So instead we've provided the
因此我们转而提供
Quick Look simulator to launch
Quick Look Simulator 以便启动
your extension for you and it
你的 Extension
will stick around while you
它在你调试时并不会消失
So, let's take a look at how
那么让我们来看看
that works.
它是如何工作的吧
All right, so let's take a look
好了 现在我们来看看
at the Mac version of the app.
这个 App 的 Mac 版本
So here we have the same app
我们现在看到了和 iOS 版本
that we saw on iOS.
一样的 App
It's got a list of pictures, if
这里有一个图片列表
you select a picture you get a
如果你选择其中一张
more detailed view with a title
就能看到更详细的视图
and a larger picture.
并带有标题和稍大的图片
Let's see what happens if we
我们来看一下 如果在 Spotlight 中
search for it in Spotlight.
搜索它 会发生什么情况
We get a big blank space.
只有一大片空白区域
Let's see if we can fix that.
我们来看看能不能调整好
So, I'm going to create another
这次我要用
target this time with the macOS
macOS 的 Quick Look 预览 Extension 模板
Quick Look preview extension
创建另一个目标
template and we'll call that
我们将调用 iOS 的
pictures preview extension for
图片预览 Extension
Go ahead and activate it.
我们继续操作 激活它
And again, I'm going to import
我要再一次
the framework.
引入这个框架
That one and jump to prepare
就是它  然后跳转到
preview of searchable item which
准备可搜索项目的预览
is the same method that you saw
这与你在 iOS 上看到的方法
on iOS.
相同
So, we're going to do the same
这里我们要进行
thing here and use that
同样的操作
identifier to get a picture with
使用那个标识符
the matching identifier and then
找到带有匹配标识符的图片
we're going to go ahead and set
之后继续设置我们的
up our view.
视图
This is the same view that you
这与你在 App 里看到的
saw in the app, I'm going to add
视图一样 我要把它添加到
it to our view hierarchy, do a
我们的视图层级中
little printout so we know when
设定一个 PrintOut 语句
we've attached and finally, we
这样我们就能得知连接成功了
call that completion handler.
最后 我们要调用完成句柄
So, let's give that a go.
那么 让我们开始运行它吧
When you run your Quick Look
当你运行 Quick Look 预览
preview extension Xcode will
Extension 时 Xcode将会
offer the Quick Look simulator
默认提供 Quick Look
by default.
模拟器
So, go ahead and select that.
好  我们来选中它
And there's a Quick Look
这就是 Quick Look
simulator.
模拟器了
On the left you will see your
在左侧你将看到你的
Core Spotlight items.
Core Spotlight 各项目
If you have a lot of index
如果有很多索引搜索结果
search results you can use the
你可以使用上面的
search field above to narrow it
搜索字段来缩小
down.
范围
When you select one of these
当你在这些结果里选中
results your preview will appear
其中一条时  你的预览将会出现
on the right and you can see
在右侧  这样你就能看到
that Xcode has successfully
Xcode 已成功地
attached and you can go ahead
实现连接
and debug to your heart's
现在你可以随心所欲地
content.
进行调试了
So, let's see what it looks like
我们就来看一看它在
in Spotlight now.
Spotlight 中是什么样子
So, as you can see Spotlight has
大家可以看到  Spotlight已经成功
successfully replaced the blank
使用你的 Extension 填充了
spot with your extension.
原本的空白区域
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, as you saw, the API for Core
大家看到了吧  macOS 中
Spotlight previews on macOS is
Core Spotlight 预览的 API
identical to the one on iOS.
与 iOS 中的 API 是一样的
Some final tips here.
最后再提供一些小建议
One caveat to remember is that
需要谨记的一点是 大家不应该在
you should not make any views in
Extension 的第一道响应程序里
your extension first responder.
查看任何视图
Your preview is not meant to be
你的预览并不是交互式的
interactive, Spotlight is the
Spotlight 才是这种情况下的
interactive element here.
交互元素
And finally, the Quick Look
最后 macOS 中的
preview extension on macOS only
Quick Look 预览 Extension
supports Core Spotlight items.
仅仅支持 Core Spotlight 项
For file-based previews the
对基于文件的预览来说
classic Quick Look generator API
经典的 Quick Look 生成器 API
is still the solution.
仍是它的解决办法
So that's it for Core Spotlight
以上就是有关 Core Spotlight
previews.
预览的内容
Back to John.
我们再次有请 John
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Lyn, that was great.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢 Lyn  非常精彩的讲解
Ranking is very important for
对 Spotlight 而言 排名是非常
Spotlight.
重要的
In iOS 11 and macOS [inaudible]
在 iOS 11 和 macOS High Sierra 中
we've added a new machine
我们为 Core Spotlight 添加了
learning based ranker for Core
一种新的基于机器学习的
Spotlight.
排名算法
This is personalized and
它很有个性  而且适应力
adaptive, it runs on device
很强  它借助于 Core ML
using Core ML and we've worked
在设备上运行  我们付出了很大努力
very hard to keep your data
以确保大家私人数据的
private.
安全性
All the personalization and
用户所有的个性化设置与
adaptation to the user happens
调适都是在设备上
on device.
进行的
The ML model is trained in the
ML 模型在云端训练
cloud using features known
使用的是 从各位的本地设备上
locally from your devices.
获取的特性
Features are private, they do
这些特性属于隐私  它们并不
not include actual results and
包括实际结果
they do not include actual
也不包括实际
queries.
查询
Data for training is only
用于训练模型的数据
submitted if you're opted in to
只有当你被选入进行设备分析时
device analytics.
才会被提交
This is a privacy friendly way
在进行机器学习时
of doing machine learning.
这能很好地保护隐私
We've also added some new
我们还添加了一些新的属性
properties to let you help us
以便让大家帮助我们
rank your content.
为各位的内容进行排名
We've added a rankingHint which
我们添加了一个 rankingHint
is a number from 1 to 100 with
它是在 1 至 100 之间的一个数字
100 being the best.
其中 100 代表最好
And when the ranker can't tell
当排名算法无法区分
the difference between items
两项之间的差别时
this can be used to elevate the
它就可以派上用场
more important content.
把更重要的内容提到前面
A new Boolean attribute was
我们已经创建了新的布尔属性
This lets us know whether the
这可以让我们知道用户
user created the item.
是否新建了项目
UserOwned lets us know whether
UserOwned 则让我们知道
the user has purchased this
用户是否购买了这个
item.
项目
And userCurated lets us know
UserCurated 能让我们得知
whether this is an item that the
这一项目是否
user selected, for example a
是用户自选 比如说
bookmarked news article.
一篇加了书签的新闻报道
Now keep in mind that this is
大家要记住 这只是
just input to the ranker.
对排名算法的信息输入
If you try to fool the ranking
如果你想和排名系统开个玩笑
system by setting the
并且用 rankingHint 把
rankingHint at everything to 100
每个项目都设置为 100
it won't really affect anything.
这样做并不会有什么影响
This is only for ranking within
这只是在你自己的
your own items.
项目内部的排名
Match quality and usage
匹配质量和使用信息
information is still critical
仍然是影响排名的
for ranking.
关键因素
So, to get the best ranking
所以 为了获取最佳排名表现
behavior use NSUserActivity so
就使用 NSUserActivity 吧
that we know what the user
这样我们可以得知用户
interacts with in your app.
在你的 App 里的交互情况
Provide a rich metadata for the
为排名算法的继续运行而
ranker to work on, so set a
提供丰富的元数据
great title, set an informative
例如设置一个好的标题
description, specify dates, and
设定信息内容丰富的描述 明确日期
judiciously use keywords to make
并合理使用关键词 使
items easier to find, but don't
项目更容易查找
misuse keywords because straight
但不要误用关键词
keyword matches means that your
因为直白的关键词匹配
application's results will rank
意味着你的应用程序的
lower.
排名结果将会靠后
Now let's get back to basics.
现在我们回到基础步骤
You need to get content into the
你需要将内容添加到索引里
index and the primary way to add
而添加内容的基本方法是
content is directly via the
直接通过
CSSearchable index API.
CSSearchable 索引 API
Secondarily, you can also index
其次 你也可以给
NSUserActivity which we
NSUserActivity 创建索引
recommend doing because it
我们建议大家这样做
provides an important ranking
因为它可以提供非常重要的
signal.
排序信号
Sometimes you'll need to delete
有时你需要删除那些
items reacting to what the user
对用户操作或外部事件
does or to external events.
作出反应的项目
And of course, we have APIs for
当然 对此我们
that as well.
也有适用的 API
Adding CSSearchableItems to the
把 CSSearchableItems
index is quite easy and you're
添加至索引  是非常简单的事
in complete control of what you
你可以完全掌控添加的内容
You first create a CSSearchable
首先你要创建一个
item attribute set that will
CSSearchable 项目属性集
hold the metadata for the item.
它将为项目储存元数据
You initialize the attribute set
你要将属性集符
with the universal type
通过通用型标识进行初始化
Here we're using kUTTypeImage
这里我们要使用 kUTTypeImage
with a generic type frame rich
它有泛型框架以及丰富的内容
You also want to use something
你还要采用一些更具体的方式
more specific and there are many
这个体系有很多的
built-in types of the system to
内置类型可以
inherit from.
获得延用
It's important in iOS and
使用正确的类型
critical in macOS that you use
在 iOS 中很重要
the right type because it
在 macOS 中很关键
affects where and how your
因为这会影响到你的内容
content is displayed.
位置以及呈现方式
Then you set some attributes and
然后你要设定一些属性和
the attribute set display name
属性集显示名称
is a bare minimum.
这是最基本的
You create a searchable item
你创建了一个带有特殊标识符的
with a unique identifier, a
可检索项目
domain identifier and the
一个域标识符和
attribute set.
属性集
And keep in mind that unique
记住 当 Spotlight 要
identifier is what you'll get
在你的应用里启动时
back when Spotlight wants to
你将重新获得的东西
launch into your application.
就是特殊标识符
And you index it and the
你将把它编入索引
completion handler will get
完成句柄将会被调用
called and the data has been
而数据已经被安全地
safely committed to storage.
存入库中
Just like for Spotlight
就像 Spotlight 的情况一样
NSUserActivity can be used to
NSUserActivity 可以
index content and navigation
将你 App 里的内容和路径点
points in your app.
编入索引
NSUserActivity reflects what the
NSUserActivity 反映出
user has done in the
用户在应用里做过的事
application, whereas
而 CSSearchable
CSSearchable reflects what your
则反映出你的 App
app has to offer.
必须提供的东西
So, the difference is that the
因此  它们的不同之处在于
Core Spotlight API lets you
Core Spotlight API 可以
index items that the user hasn't
让你把用户还没有
visited and is generally
访问过的条目编入索引
preferable as it gives you
人们普遍都会选用它
complete control over what is
因为它可以让你完全掌控
indexed.
被加入索引的内容
But on the other hand, because
但另一方面
NSUserActivity is only for items
因为 NSUserActivity 只针对用户
that the user has visited it
已经访问过的项目
provides that important signal
它为排序提供
for ranking.
重要信号
To use NSUserActivity to inform
如果想要通过 NSUserActivity
ranking you need to relate them
了解排序情况
to the CSSearchableItems that
你需要把它们关联到你创建索引的
you index.
CSSearchableItems
To do this when you create your
为了做到这一点  当你在创建
NSUserActivity you also create
NSUserActivity 时
an attribute set.
也是在创建一个属性集
You set properties on the
你需要给属性集添加属性
attribute set and then you set
然后你需要设置
the related unique identifier or
相关的特殊标识符
if you don't want the lifetime
或者是  如果你不想让
of your NSUserActivity tied to
NSUserActivity 的使用寿命
your Core Spotlight items use
绑定在 Core Spotlight 项目上
the [inaudible] related unique
那么你就使用与 [音质不清晰]
identifier instead.
相关的特殊标识符
Then you mark your user activity
然后你再把你的用户活动
as eligible for search and you
标记为可搜索
set the attribute set on the
再对用户活动的
user activity.
属性集进行设置
The many reasons to delete items
删除项目的理由有很多
from reacting to user's actions
从应对用户的行为
to getting rid of stale content.
到删除过时内容  一应俱全
Using the Core Spotlight API you
使用 Core Spotlight API
can delete specific items by
你就可以通过具体项目的标识符
their identifiers.
来删除它们
For example, if the user deletes
比如 如果用户删除了一个
a document.
文件
You can delete groups of items
你可以利用多组项目的
by their domain identifier which
领域标识符  把它们统统删除
can be useful if the user signs
如果用户要退出账号或
out of account or ends a
停止订阅
subscription and you want to
而你想要删除所有内容时
remove all content for it.
这个方法可能会奏效
You can also use this to delete
你也可以用同样的方法
NSUserActivities that you've
来删除已经编入索引的 NSUserActivities
indexed if you set the domain
前提是你在它们上面
identifier on them.
设定了领域标识符
Finally, you can delete all
最后 你可以删除应用中
searchable items for your
所有的可搜索项目
applications, which is useful if
如果你更换了版本并且
you have a version change and
需要重新创建索引的话
you need to restart indexing.
这样的方法是很有用的
This is also called on your
如果用户要删除一个应用
behalf when the user deletes an
这也是以你的名义
application.
调用的
Now let's get into the details
现在我们来具体说说
of indexing Core Spotlight.
为 Core Spotlight 创建索引的事
Let's start with how to register
我们先说说如何注册
as an index delete and then talk
索引委托 然后再谈谈如何
about how to build a Core
建立 Core Spotlight Extension
Spotlight extension which does
它可以在你的 App
the job of a delegate when your
停止工作时
app isn't running.
完成委托
We'll talk about how client
我们将讨论客户状态
state works and how you can use
怎样运作以及如何通过它
it to make indexing robust and
让你的索引功能强大而
efficient.
有效
And we'll discuss some
我们也会探讨一些
performance considerations.
性能注意事项
Registering as an index delegate
以索引委托进行注册  可以
lets Spotlight reach out to your
在我们需要你有所行动的时候
app when we need you to take
让 Spotlight 联系到你的 App
It lets us request that you
这导致我们请求大家
index all your content or index
把所有的内容都加入索引
particular items [inaudible]
或者把特定项目加入索引 [音源不清楚]
accurate and up-to-date.
以确保精确和时效
It's also responsible for
它还负责响应
responding to index throttling
Index Throttling
and for providing Drag-and-Drop
并向拖放操作
data.
提供数据
As usual, setting up the
和通常情况一样 设定委托
delegate is just a single line
只需要使用一行代码
of code, but to be a delegate
但是承担委托
you need to implement the
你却需要执行
CSSearchableIndex delegate
CSSearchableIndex 委托协议
This is a complete protocol.
这是一份完整的协议
The first two methods are
前两种方法是必须的
required, we look at those in a
我们稍后再进行
bit more detail in a moment.
更具体的介绍
The second two are optional and
接下来的两个方法是备选用的
let you know that indexing has
它们告诉你  创建索引的过程已减慢
been slowed down to favor
以便支持前台活动
foreground activity giving you
从而让你可以选择停止
the option of stopping any
所有不重要的
noncritical indexing and
索引进程
focusing on the most important
或者只关注最重要的项目
And finally, there are the two
最后 这是我们先前
methods for Drag-and-Drop that
说过用于拖放的
we discussed earlier.
两种方法
When the index all method is
当全体索引的方法被调用时
called you add everything to the
你会将一切都加入
index.
这个索引
And when you get the call back
当你收到最后一个项目的
for the last item you call the
回调时  你会调用
acknowledgment handler.
确认句柄
If your app quits and is
如果你的 App 退出
relaunched before the handler is
然后又在句柄被调用前重新启动
called the Spotlight will call
Spotlight 就会以
that again with the same
同样的回调方式
callback.
来调用它
When reindex items with
当经过重新索引  并带有识别符的
identifiers is called you look
项目被调用时
up the items the Spotlight is
你要查找下述项目
requesting and re-add or delete
即 Spotlight 要求以妥当形式重新加入
them as appropriate.
或删除的那些项目
And again, you call
再次强调 你只有在
acknowledgment handler only when
收到任务出色完成后
you've received the last
最终返回的回调函数
callback for any outstanding
才能够调用
work.
确认句柄
The Core Spotlight extension
Core Spotlight Extension
implements a CSSearchableIndex
执行 CSSearchableIndex 委托协议
delegate protocol and allows
并在你的 App
callbacks to happen when your
处于非工作状态时
app is not running.
使用回调函数
This gets your content back into
这可以在用户从备份中恢复
Spotlight as quickly as possible
或者需要数据灾备
after the user is restored from
的时候
backup or when disaster recovery
让你的内容尽快返回
is needed.
Spotlight
The Core Spotlight extension
Core Spotlight Extension
will be called before your items
会在你的项目失效前被调用
expire allowing you to update
以便你对它们进行
them if necessary, even if the
必要的更新 即便是用户
user happens to not be using
恰好没有在使用
your application.
你的应用
Since the interface extension is
因为界面扩展与
the same as for the index
索引委托是一样的
delegate it's best to factor
所以最好对你的代码进行因子排列
your code so that you can share
这样你就可以
the implementation.
参与执行过程了
And ideally, the shared
理想的情况是
implementation will live in the
参与的执行过程
framework.
存在于框架之内
Remember also that the Core
同时也要记住
Spotlight extension is critical
Core Spotlight Extension 对于
to support Drag-and-Drop.
支持拖放而言非常关键
If you don't have an extension
如果你没有 Extension
there will be nothing to call
当用户向你在另一个 App 的
when the user drops an item for
应用程序里拖放条目时
your application in another app.
就没有东西可调用
Well you can get the indexing
当然你可以在不使用客户端状态的
right without using client
情况下获得创建索引的
state.
权利
We found that it makes the task
我们发现这可以让任务变得
far easier.
更简单
Client state allows you to keep
客户端状态可以让
Spotlight and your own database
你的 Spotlight 与你的数据库同步
in sync without redundant work.
并且无需繁冗操作
Client state is an opaque
客户端状态是一种
Spotlight.
模糊的 Spotlight
What it is is your choice.
它的性质由你来决定
It's often a simple integer
它通常是一个简单的整数
denoting a sequence number which
代表一串序列号
could be in a marker in a
这串序列号在数据库日志中
database journal, but we've seen
被标记出来
more complex cases as well.
但是我们也见过更复杂的例子
Let's look at how this works.
我们来看看它是怎么一回事
Your app sends batches to Core
你的 App 向 Core Spotlight
Spotlight, each batch is
发送了批任务
journaled with the client state.
每个批任务都有客户端状态日志
When the batch has been
当批任务依照日志而展开进行时
committed to the journal your
你的回调日志就
callback log is called letting
被调用了
you know that the batch has been
以便让你知道  批任务已被接收
So here the app is just indexing
这里的 App 只是将一个新的
a new batch, but disaster
批任务加入索引
strikes and the app crashes.
但会导致灾难降临 让 App 崩溃
Now what happened to the data
当元数据中发生的情况
that was in flight, did it make
是未提交的状态
it to the index?
可以通过索引找到吗
With client state, you can find
用客户端状态
out.
你就可以找到它
When your app starts again you
当你的 App 再次启动时
request the client state.
你请求用户端状态
Here you get state two back
现在你收到了状态二
since this was last state that
因为这实际上是日志中的
actually made it into the
最后一个状态
journal and you can restart
你正好可以在正确的节点
indexing at just the right
重新开始创建
point.
索引
If the data had already made it
如果 App 出现崩溃时
to the Core Spotlight process
数据在 Core Spotlight 的程序中
when the crash happened you
已经实现了这一点
could continue it from state
你就可以从状态三继续
three instead, so you do the
这样一来你的工作量
minimal amount of work.
就会很少
To store client state, you need
要想保存用户端状态
to create a named index.
你需要创建一个命名索引
You can't use the default
你不能使用这个默认
instance.
示例
The name lets us know which
从命名我们就可以知道
states to fetch which is
哪个是要提取的
required because some apps need
哪个是被请求的 因为
more than one token.
有些 App 需要的代表符号不止一个
For example, because they're
比如 因为它们是
multiple databases.
复合数据库
So, in your code first you
所以 在你的代码中
create a named index instance,
你首先需要创建命名索引实例
you'll begin an index batch, you
你会开始建立索引批任务
add searchable items as usual,
像平常一样加入可搜索项目
and then you compute the state
然后你需要计算
that you want to save.
想要存储的状态
Finally, you end the batch with
最终你用你的模糊状态
your opaque state and pay
结束批任务
attention to any errors returned
注意完成句柄返回的
with the completion handler.
所有错误
So, at some later point when
所以  在这后面的一些节点上
you're app or extension starts
你的 App 或 Extension 开始
use client state to resume
利用客户端状态
indexing.
继续开始索引
You fetch the client state and
你读取客户端状态
you compare it to the current
把它和当前状态进行比较
state doing whatever work is
再想尽办法
needed to bring them in sync.
让它们保持同步
So, in your code you create an
所以 在你的代码里
index instance for the same
你为同一名称创建了索引实例
name, you fetch the client
你读取到客户端状态
state, you examine the state
在处理完所有的错误后
after dealing with any errors,
检查状态
and then you just pick up where
然后根据需要
you left off if required.
只从原先中断的地方继续
And so, you can replay exactly
这样你就可以重新进行
the operations that are needed
必要的操作
to bring your index and Core
从而让你的索引和
Spotlight in sync.
Core Spotlight 同步
Let's talk some more about
我们再来说说
indexing performance.
索引的性能表现
Indexing is a background task
索引是一个后台任务
and you don't want to slow down
你肯定不想让索引工作
your app or the device with
拖慢你的 App 或设备
indexing work.
运行速度
So, minimize overhead, optimize
所以  系统负担要最小化
any access to the file system or
要优化对文件系统或数据库的访问
databases that you have to do in
唯有如此
order to create items.
你才能创建各种项目
And remember that each call to
记住 Core Spotlight 的每次调用
Core Spotlight carries overhead.
都产生系统开销
So, has batches of items instead
所以只要有可能  就应当使用
of single items whenever it's
批处理项目 而不是
possible.
单个项目
That said, consider that memory
也就是说 鉴于存储空间有限
is limited, so keep your batches
所以你要将批量控制在
reasonably small.
合理的小范围内
Even batching just 10 items
即使每一批次只有 10 个项
decreases the overhead by an
也会逐级按规模地增加
order of magnitude.
系统开销
And it's often more efficient to
多数情况下 以流水线形式
give multiple batches in flight
进行多批次处理
in the pipeline manner than to
相比使用单个大批量处理
use a single large batch.
更有效率
This allows indexing to happen
这样可以让索引和你的工作
in parallel with your work.
平行开展
Sine your app will be indexing
因为这样一来
while it's in use don't block
你的 App 在使用过程中
the main thread.
创建索引也不会阻碍主线程
And finally, index on a
最后 在后台排队进行索引
background queue this will help
将有助于提高功效和
with power and responsiveness.
反应快捷的程度
To get a great presentation in
要想让 Spotlight 的内容显得美观
Spotlight you want to set a good
你需要建立一个
thumbnail.
好的缩略图
By default, Spotlight will use
在默认状态下  Spotlight 会使用
your app icon, which makes it
你的 App 图标
hard to distinguish results at a
这让人很难一眼就区分出
glance.
结果
Just as important the thumbnail
与缩略图同样重要的是
is a title, the title is not
项目的标题  这个标题
just created visually, it's also
不仅是视觉直观意义上的  它也是
what users most frequently
用户们最常搜索的
search on.
目标
After the thumbnail and the
在设置好缩略图和标题后
title, you're going to set other
你需要设置其他
fields that are suitable for
适用于个人联系的
your contact.
字段
Your description creates a much
你的描述可以提供更为
richer result and providing the
丰富的信息
content creation date can be
显示内容创建的时间
very helpful as well.
也很有帮助
Where appropriate, rating and
只要出现在合适的地方
rating description can make a
排名和排名描述
big difference.
也能发挥重大作用
And if you know the location for
如果你知道某个应用所在的位置
something, setting the location
设定位置名称
name can be a very nice touch.
算得上是很好的尝试
So, set a title, provide a great
因此  设置好标题
thumbnail, and set the right
提供一个好的缩略图
content type for your content.
并且给你的内容设置正确的内容类型
Then fill out the UI with
然后用补充的元数据
additional metadata to write a
填写用户界面
great visual representation of
创造出内容方面的最佳
your content.
视觉展示效果
And remember that setting the
要记住 设置正确的元数据
right metadata isn't just about
不仅只是考虑到外观效果
looks it also affects behavior,
它还会对行为产生影响
so let's take a look at that.
我们来看看这个
For starters, enabling quick
对于初学者来说
actions like directions and
增强快速操作功能 例如指示和调用
calling makes the user interface
可以让用户的界面更丰富
richer and provides great value
而且能够给用户带来
to the user.
更大价值
To support navigation, you set
为了支持导航功能
the latitude and longitude
你需要设置
attributes and set supports
经纬度属性  并将导航支持
navigation to true.
设置为 True
Similarly, to support phone
同样 为了支持电话功能
calls, you need to set the phone
你需要设置电话号码属性
numbers attribute and set
并将支持导航设置为
supports navigation to true
True 抱歉说错了
sorry, and set phone call to
应该是将呼叫行为设置为
true.
True
Setting attributes that the user
设置用户能够理解的属性
can understand makes it easy to
能够使得搜索
search.
更加方便
And setting attributes that
设置与项目本身
aren't naturally associated with
并没有多少自然联系的属性
the item makes it hard to search
会给搜索造成困难
and leads to poor ranking of
并导致你的结果在排名表现上
your results.
很糟糕
By setting contact identifiers,
通过设置联系人标识符
you can enable focus contact
你可以集中进行
search which is a great way to
联系人的搜索
get the user to your content.
这是让用户获取你内容的好办法
Supporting features like
有一些辅助特性 比如
Drag-and-Drop and Quick Actions
拖放和快速操作
makes for a first-class
它们会为你带来一流的
experience.
体验
Another part of experiences is
另一种体验  是能够
being able to engage with
让[音质不清晰]
[inaudible] in your own
融入到你自己的应用中
application, so let's look at
我们来看看它是什么
that.
情况
Make sure launching from
要确保在 Spotlight 中
Spotlight is fast and that it
快速完成搜索
takes the user directly to the
让用户可以直接启动
found items.
找到的项目
Use NSUserActivity to restore
用 NSUserActivity 来储存状态
the state, your app delegate
你的 App 委托
will be called a continuous
将是一种持续的作业
activity and your [inaudible]
你的[音质不清晰]作业类型以及
activity type and the userInfo
用户信息字典
dictionary is necessary.
则是非常有必要的
If you're being launched because
如果因为用户在 Spotlight 中
the user selected a
选择了一个 CSSearchableItem
CSSearchableItem in Spotlight
所以你要启动程序
the activity type will be the
那么这个作业类型将成为
CSSearchableItem action type and
CSSearchableItem 操作类型
the unique identifier can be
使用 CSSearchableItem
retrieved from the userInfo
作业标识符
dictionary by using
就可以从用户信息字典里
CSSearchableItem activity
获取到独一无二的
identifier.
标识符
Another reason for being
启动作业的另一个原因是
launched is that the user wants
用户想要
to continue the search in your
在你的应用里
application.
继续搜索
In that case, you get the
在这种情况下
CSQueryContinuation action type
你得到的是 CSQueryContinuation
and you can retrieve the search
操作类型  这样就可以利用
query using the
CSSearchQueryString
CSSearchQueryString from the
从用户信息字典中找到
userInfo dictionary.
搜索查询内容
Of course, the search system
当然 如果没有搜索 API
wouldn't be complete without a
搜索系统便是
search API.
不完整的
Core Spotlight provides the
Core Spotlight 能够
ability to search the data that
帮助搜索你已经提供的
you have provided.
数据
It's the same search engine
这是系统里多处使用到的
that's used in many places on
同一种搜索
the system.
引擎
By using it you get consistent
通过使用它  你可以
behavior with Spotlight and the
持续地使用 Spotlight 和
system applications.
系统应用
It's great for all your content
这对于你设备中的
on the device and of course, it
所有内容都非常有益
works in both iOS and macOS.
当然了 它在 iOS 和 macOS 里均可使用
You can query for equality, for
你可以查询规格大小相同的项目
greater than or less than.
也更以查找更大一些 或稍小一些的项目
So, if you want to find items
所以  如果你想要查找
with more than a certain number
超过一定页数的项目
of pages the query is very short
查询语句是非常
and simple.
简短的
If you want to find all items
如果你想找到页数限定
with page count in a certain
在一定范围内的所有项目
range you can use the InRange
你可以使用 InRange 运算符
operator.
你还可以使用
for example, to select only
布尔运算符 比如说 用它来
items for the given width and
筛选符合特定宽度和高度的
height.
项目
You can use string matching with
你可以使用配有旗标的字符串
flags that makes Spotlight's
来改变 Spotlight 匹配的
matching more or less strict.
严格程度
From use in case insensitive
关于采用敏感度较低的
word matching [inaudible]
文字匹配
insensitive matching to other
[音质不清晰]
combinations of flags or to
与其他带有旗标的组合形成不敏感的匹配
strict matching of full fields.
或是符合所有字段的严格匹配
Or you can make your matching
或者说  你可以让自己匹配标准非常宽松
very laxed and treat each word
把每个单词都当成
as an individual query.
一次独立查询
This is what Spotlight itself
这就是 Spotlight 的工作机制
does so if you want to be
如果你想要前后保持一致
consistent it's a good place to
从这里开始 是一个不错的
start.
选择
And of course, if this doesn't
当然 如果这不适合你的应用程序
suit your own application you
你可以按照自己的意愿
can combine and mix-and-match as
进行自由组合 或是
you like.
混合搭配
Core Spotlight supports a full
Core Spotlight 支持全系列的
range of operators for
比较运算符
comparison and Boolean logic and
和布尔逻辑
of course, you can nest
当然 你可以用圆括号
expressions using parentheses.
来嵌入表达内容
The field wildcard will match
字段通配符将会匹配
any default search metadata and
所有默认搜索的元数据
the double wildcard will match
而双通配符会
that, as well as text content.
与之匹配  它与文本内容也同样匹配
We have a number of options for
对于字符串的匹配
string matching.
我们有很多选择
Our index is heavily optimized
我们的索引已经很大程度上
for exact and prefix search and
优化了精确搜索和前缀搜索
it's incredibly fast if you use
如果使用这些方法 你会发现
these.
它的速度快得惊人
As a general rule, the longer
一般情况下
the prefix the faster the query.
前缀越长  查询越快
Partial matching is very similar
部分匹配与前缀匹配
to prefix matching, depending on
极为相似  关键是要看
the string whichever has your
哪种方法可以更快得到结果
results is faster.
这取决于字符串
Phrase matching which means
词组匹配意味着只是
matching only on consecutive
匹配连续的几个词
words is significantly more
它耗费的资源肯定更高一些
And finally, suffix and infix
最后是后缀和内缀匹配
matching are all slower and
它们速度会更慢
using phrase matching combined
这些内容  再加上词组匹配
with these multiplies the cost.
导致所需时间也大大增加
The query syntax also offers a
查询句法也会提供一组旗标
set of flags that you can apply
通过它们
to make the matching less
你可以让匹配规则少一些
strict.
严苛条件
The C is for case insensitive, D
这个 C 代表不区分大小写
is for diacritics insensitive,
D 代表不区分变音符号
which means that characters like
这是说像这样的
an over [inaudible] can still be
字符仍然能够
matched with an old character if
与某个旧字符相匹配
the user is using the English
如果用户的本地语言
locale.
是英语的话
Word matching means that we
逐字匹配的意思是
match words internal to fields
我们将词汇与字段内部
instead of just being anchored
相匹配
at the beginning of a field.
而不仅是锁定于字段的开端
And T for tokenized breaks out
T 代表令牌化
the individual words of the
它把查询里的单个单词进行了拆解
So, let's look at an example.
我们来看一个例子
We're implementing a search
我们正在执行搜索功能
function that takes a user query
我们把用户的查询
as input.
作为输入
First, we make sure to cancel
首先 我们要确保取消
any currently running query so
当前所有正在运行的查询
that we don't have multiple
这样我们就不会有多个
concurrent queries as this will
同时发生的查询
slow down the new query.
因为这样会使新的查询速度变慢
Since it's user input we make
因为它是由用户输入
sure to state the query string.
我们要确保对查询字符串作出说明
We then use the double star
然后我们用双星句法和
syntax with cdwmt operators to
Cdwmt 运算符
make a very forgiving query.
来开展一次很不严格的查询
We create the query object
我们创建一个查询对象
specifying that we want to fetch
具体就是我们想获取
the display names.
显示名称
We set the found items handler
我们设置查找项目句柄
and then we set the completion
然后设置
handler.
完成句柄
The completion handler will get
只有从查询中得不到更多结果时
called only when there are no
完成句柄才会
more results to receive from the
被调用
query while the found items
而查找项目句柄
handler can be called with
可以
multiple batches of results.
被多批结果调用
After that all they need to do
之后他们需要做的就是
is start the query, that's how
开始查询
easy it is to use the Core
使用 Core Spotlight 搜索 API
Spotlight search API.
就是这么容易
So, in summary Core Spotlight is
总之  现在的 Core Spotlight
now available for the Mac, as
可用于 Mac
well as iOS and it's great for
也可用于 iOS
all your managed content.
对于你们管理的所有内容都很有用
Please adopt the new APIs or
请大家采用新的 API
previews for Drag-and-Drop on
或者 iOS 和 macOS 上的拖放
both iOS and macOS.
预览功能
Provide a rich metadata for
为搜索 展示和排序
search, display and ranking.
提供丰富的元数据
And use NSUserActivity to
用 NSUserActivity 提供
provide usage information.
使用信息
And as always, keep the index
始终要注意的是
accurate and up-to-date by
索引的准确性
implementing indexing extension
并通过执行索引 Extension
and taking advantage of client
和利用客户端状态
state.
来更新索引
For more information, visit
更多内容请访问
developer.apple.com and you can
developer.apple.com
also watch some sessions from
大家也可以观看本周
earlier in the week if you're
较早的会议
interested in Drag-and-Drop,
如果你对拖放感兴趣
introducing Drag-and-Drop, as
这里面会有具体介绍
well as mastering Drag-and-Drop
它会推荐一些如何熟练操控
would be recommended.
拖放的内容
And if you want to know about
如果你想知道
how CoreData and Core Spotlight
CoreData 和 Core Spotlight
interact the session on what's
是如何交互的
new in CoreData is great to
“CoreData 有何创新”
watch.
这场会议也非常值得观看